A Finding Aid to the Gertrude Kasle Gallery Records, 1949-1999 (bulk 1964-1983), in the Archives of American Art AAA.gertkasl
Archives of American Art
- Gallery and Personal Business and Administrative Files, 1961-1995; Series 2; (Boxes 6-7, OV 12; 1.2 linear feet)
  - Publisher Files, 1964-1992; Subseries 4
    - Sidney Janis Gallery, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Transworld Art, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Correspondence, 1972-1990 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1975-1982 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1983-1988 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Print Descriptions, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Printed Material, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Universal Limited Art Editions-Printed Material, (Clippings), 1967-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Waddington, Graphics, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Exhibition Files, 1963-1976; Series 3; (Box 7; 7 folders)
  Scattered exhibition files are found for a few exhibitions; most are filed in the Artists Files. General information about exhibitions, such as clippings, schedules, announcements, and financial statements are found here.
  - American Folk Art, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Collage, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1963-1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Schedules, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Science in Art" Exhibition, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Universal Limited Art Editions, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Photographic Material, 1953-1985; Series 4; (Boxes 7, 10; 18 folders)
  Found here are color transparencies, black and white photographs, and slides. The majority of the photographic material consists of images of artwork by individual artists and is arranged alphabetically by artists'last name. There are also two photo portraits of artists, however, the majority of photographs of artists are located in the Artist Files.
  - Artists' Portraits, 1960s; (See Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Chryssa's Studio, 1960s; (See Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Slides-Artists: A-N, 1966-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Slides-Artists: O-Z, 1967-1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Slides: DeKooning-Goodman, 1967-1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Slides: Goodnough-Guston, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Slides: Hartigan-Indiana, 1966-1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Slides: Jenkins-Loving, 1965-1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Slides: Motherwell-Nesbitt, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Slides: Nesbitt-Rivers, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Slides: Rosenthal-Shapiro, B., 1967-1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Slides: Shapiro, B.-Yektai, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Slides: Subject Files, 1966-1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Transparencies-Goodnough, Motherwell, Natkin, Nesbitt, Schwedler, Shapiro, Unidentified, 1966-1975 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Transparencies-Nesbitt, Reinhardt, Rivers, Tworkov, 1953-1966 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Transparencies-Pollock, C., 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified Artist, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Various Unidentified Artwork, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Artists' Portraits, 1960s (Box 10 (sol))
  - Chryssa's Studio, 1960s (Box 10 (sol))
- Sound Recordings, 1966-1971; Series 5; (Boxes 7-9; 7 folders)
  Found here are recorded interviews and speeches of artists and art historians. The recording formats include audio cassette and reel to reel tapes. There are at least two separate interviews with Tatyana Grosman and Lowell Nesbitt. Transcripts are not available.
  - Interview with Tatyana Grosman, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Interview with Lowell Nesbitt, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Interviews with Tatyana Grosman, Paul Jenkins, Lowell Nesbitt, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Interviews with Tatyana Grosman and Bill Tall, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Jack Tworkov Lecture, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Paul Jenkins Lecture, Detroit Institute of Arts, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified, no date (Box 9, Folder 2)